And this is Joe Bevington.
We're sitting in Cocoa Beach Cafe,
and this is in Cornwall, UK.
I am CEO of Cook in Cornwall, CIC.
And predominantly our work is to support
new migrants to Cornwall
to promote blackness in Cornwall
as a way of feed and acceptance.
I was born in the early sixties
in West Bromwich, England,
but I grew up in the Caribbean.
And then when I was 15, I came back
to live in England with my mum.
I'm a country girl at heart.
Even when I lived in Jamaica,
I lived in Kingston
with every single opportunity
and went away to the countryside
because I think the less urban areas
afford a sense of freedom
and the opportunity to explore.
In a sense that is not contrived.
And that's one of the things that I wanted
for my child.
And I knew that
no matter
where we live, she was going to have
challenges.
So why not
support by letting her
have the freedom to space
and not the competition
against her in an urban area?
Because that can be
so much more difficult.
There was a time when you would count
how many persons of color
you saw on the cover on High Street,
and it was a couple of Christmases ago.
I stood and I was counting at
I counted 21 adults
within one hour and I was like, ooh!
And I stopped, counted.
I realized that
people were mobilized into
to come into Cornwall.
They were living here now.
It's such a beautiful thing to see.
I'm all about feeding people's soul
and their bodies and things like that.
And removing the the stigma.
My chilies that I use here,
my peppers and chilies that I use that
it's grown locally,
right by.
CORNISH People were chili enthusiasts.
And in this little café
that we've got here,
one of the joys is we can have 50 people
here.
We've got eight different nationalities,
just like joy to
where the world should be.
But we still retain our willingness,
and that is the thing.
So we're trying to engage
the younger generation
so that we can have new cultural
ambassadors, that they can be proud of
being in their skin and be part
of the new Cornwall, as I like to call it.
Traditionally,
black people have come to do the work
that no one else wanted to do
or to come and
support systems that are failing.
But I think people are yearning
for downtime
to get in connection with the soil again,
because they don't see that as work.
They see that as therapy.
But they've got the beach
and the considerato in the Atlantic,
in the CORNISH sea.
We've got the countryside,
we've got walks,
we have places that we can sit
and be safe.
What makes me smile is
see those who were here
from three years ago
now smiling, living in Cornwall.
I don't think I could go anywhere
else in the UK, my home.
I like
people to be celebrated for themselves
first
and the community that they're from after.
And Cornwall is a place as of for the fact
I celebrate my blackness, I celebrate
the fact that I'm neurodivergent
celebrate the fact I'm a female
that celebrate the fact that I'm a mother.
There's so many intersectionality
that makes up
who I am and what Kirkby stands for.
I just think that if
if our black British people
look at themselves, they'll see that
and they see how just wonderful
and the sound that we can give,
how much we have to give,
we should really take
that opportunity to give.